<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dave&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://www.dpetzel.info/tags/google/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dave&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>dave@petzel.email (David Petzel)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>dave@petzel.email (David Petzel)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2016 David Petzel</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://www.dpetzel.info/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromecast Woes</title>
      <link>http://www.dpetzel.info/post/chromecast-woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>dave@petzel.email (David Petzel)</author>
      <guid>http://www.dpetzel.info/post/chromecast-woes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got around to picking up a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chromecast&#34;&gt;Chromecast&lt;/a&gt;. I had read some reviews
so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any high expectations, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge to
tinker with it given its price point. Boy was I disappointed&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The instructions it came with made it look like it was going to be the easiest thing
I ever hooked up. The physical hookup was simple enough, but then it came time
to get it hooked up to my wireless. I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything fancy, just a Linksys
E3200 with &lt;code&gt;WPA2/WPA Mixed Mode&lt;/code&gt; security. I&amp;rsquo;ve hooked up a ton of devices
and never had any issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chromecast App was useless. It could see my Chromecast, but I
just kept getting a grey exclamation mark with a message saying it couldn&amp;rsquo;t
connect. I went back and forth with the online help and the only useful thing
I found was the link to the web based setup instructions located at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cast.google.com/chromecast/setup?np=manualsetup&#34;&gt;https://cast.google.com/chromecast/setup?np=manualsetup&lt;/a&gt;. With this I was able
able to get a little further. I got as far as it displaying a 4 letter code
for me to confirm. Once I did that, it failed to connect again. What!?!?!
You can &lt;strong&gt;obviously&lt;/strong&gt; connect, since you just synced up that 4 letter code!!!
A bunch of google searching and nothing useful. Finally for no good reason other than
a lucky guess, I changed the network type on my Laptop &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Chromecast wifi
network from Public to Home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I made that switch the Web based setup got a little bit further and it
prompted me for my wireless password. Entered and it failed to connect&amp;hellip;
For kicks I tried the application again, it was still useless, so back to the
web based setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up having to power off the Chromecast one more time and then running
through the setup wizard again. Finally I had it hooked up the wireless. While
I can appreciate the target audience probably needs the &amp;laquo;magic config&amp;raquo; I really
wish they would have just given me the &amp;laquo;I know what the eff I&amp;rsquo;m doing&amp;raquo; option
and just entered my wifi info directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had it connected, the native casting support in YouTube worked really well
I have a YouTube app native on my TV and the quality of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chromecast&#34;&gt;Chromecast&lt;/a&gt; was
better than the native app. Sadly, the &amp;laquo;cast my Chrome tab&amp;raquo; option didn&amp;rsquo;t have
the same quality. I tried to play a recent episode of the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbs.com/shows/big_bang_theory/&#34;&gt;The Big Bang Theory&lt;/a&gt;,
but the quality was terrible and it kept freezing. It was not watchable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next test I did was to stream the Thursday Night Football game from nfl.com
This was a little better but still pretty choppy. I was able to reduce the
choppiness by dropping the quality down to 480p. Given that I cut the cord a
while back, the fact that I was able to watch a game that was not broadcast
on one of the national network channels was pretty cool. The game was watchable
(its playing as I write this), but its certainly not a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So at the end of the day, the only thing I would consider a success was the YouTube
integration, but given I have the YouTube native app on my TV, I really don&amp;rsquo;t feel like
I gained anything. If your a techy/gadget person its worth the $35 as something fun
to play with, but as of right now I struggle to see it being a valuable addition
to my media consumption choices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>