<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dave&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://www.dpetzel.info/tags/cloud-zoom/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dave&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>dave@petzel.email (David Petzel)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>dave@petzel.email (David Petzel)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2016 David Petzel</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://www.dpetzel.info/tags/cloud-zoom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Zoom Is Blocking My Modal Dialog Box</title>
      <link>http://www.dpetzel.info/post/programming/Cloud%20Zoom%20Is%20Blocking%20My%20Modal%20Dialog%20Box/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>dave@petzel.email (David Petzel)</author>
      <guid>http://www.dpetzel.info/post/programming/Cloud%20Zoom%20Is%20Blocking%20My%20Modal%20Dialog%20Box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The issue I was having is that the Cloud Zoom enhanced image was being
displayed in front of my drop down menu as well as my modal dialog box. At
first I had only noticed the issue on the drop menu, and was having a hard time
figuring out what was going on, and thought perhaps I had done something wrong
on the superfish menu. Once I noticed it was also affecting my modal dialog,
I became suspicious of cloud zoom.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got a page that is using a few different jQuery dependent features/functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using the superfish drop down menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also using the jQuery UI Dialog for a modal dialog box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally, I&amp;rsquo;m using Cloud Zoom for some image excitement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went through and tried a few different things, and finally just disabled
cloud zoom. At that point my drop down menu was now correctly displayed over
top of the image. I spent some time looking through the cloud-zoom site with no
luck. I spent quite a bit of time googling with no luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned my attention to the jQuery UI documentation for anything that might be
a clue. I was reading through the various options and came upon the zIndex
option. I had no idea what zIndex was (I am no jQuery expert). Long story short,
I finally got to this article: &lt;a href=&#34;http://zenverse.net/how-to-fix-superfish-dropdown-menu-that-appear-under-floating-divs-in-ie6/&#34;&gt;http://zenverse.net/how-to-fix-superfish-dropdown-menu-that-appear-under-floating-divs-in-ie6/&lt;/a&gt;
So I randomly picked a stupid high zIndex (100,000), and sure enough it worked!
So the question of the day is WHY? and what is the value of zIndex I need to
use? Well on a hunch I started digging through the cloud zoom javascript and
found line 350::&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;  $(this).wrap(&#39;&amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;wrap&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;top:0px;z-index:9999;position:relative;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&#39;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Cloud Zoom is using 9999. Any other components that has a z-index lower
than that will be displayed behind my images. So of course, I put this to the
test. I set my z-index to 10,000 on my menu and 10,001 on my modal dialog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick refresh and everything is working perfect!. zIndex&amp;hellip; who knew&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you are wondering, yes I did test an iteration with the index of the
menu and modal dialog set to be lower than 9999 and as expected they were
hidden by the cloud zoom image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>