<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abouts on Dave&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://www.dpetzel.info/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abouts on Dave&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>dave@petzel.email (David Petzel)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>dave@petzel.email (David Petzel)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2016 David Petzel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 09:48:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.dpetzel.info/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://www.dpetzel.info/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 09:48:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>dave@petzel.email (David Petzel)</author>
      <guid>http://www.dpetzel.info/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a technology enthusiast, husband, dad, and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geocaching.com/profile/?guid=2b261b0d-15e3-4c16-902f-a51932dd9ff5&#34;&gt;Geocacher&lt;/a&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in technology for most of my working years. Even before that I had
an interest in computers dating all the way back to my very first PC, a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tandy_1000&#34;&gt;Tandy 1000&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up (professionally) on the enterprise IT side of things, but later on
moved into the web space (where I am today). I find the pace at which things
move on the Internet interesting and exciting. There is never any shortage of
new things to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started this site as a place to start collecting notes and thoughts on various
things I was learning about and/working on. I&amp;rsquo;ve found over the years that
you&amp;rsquo;ll spend a lot of time researching and learning how to do something and
then about 6 months after you put it down you need it for real.
At that point, you forget all the nuances of the thing you were doing. I generally
try to keep some notes about these sorts of things, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never stored them
in a way that made them easy to find again later. So I decided this would
be that place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Opensource, but I don&amp;rsquo;t generally find the time to contribute
back as much as I would like to. If you are curious what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to
latetly &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dpetzel&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; is a pretty good way to keep
tabs on me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>